-== 字幕制作：Meky ==- -==校对&时间轴: Meky ==-
耶!
Yeah!
五月十五这一天 在丛林里的某个角落
On the 15th of May, in the jungle of Nool,
夏日炎炎，在清凉的水池里
in the heat of the day, in the cool of the pool,
大象荷顿正在玩水 享受丛林生活最棒的时刻
he was splashing, enjoying the jungle's great joys,
这时他突然听到一个细微的声音
when Horton the Elephant heard a small noise.
-荷顿! -荷顿!
- Horton! - Horton!
早，同学们，准备上课了？
Good morning, class. Are you ready?
-对! -那就上来吧!
- Yeah! - Jump on board!
下面的注意!
Look out below!
汤米上来了，凯蒂，你呢？
Tommy's on board. Katie, you there?
很好
Okay.
就是那个
There it is.
这是丛林里最奇特的生物之一 拟叶虫
This is one of the jungle's most amazing creatures, the leaf bug.
为了让自己不被掠食者嗑掉 它们会伪装成一片片的叶子
In order to protect itself from predators, it disguises itself as a leaf.
这个小家伙有点固执 来吧，小家伙
This one's got quite a grip. Come on, little buddy.
别害羞嘛
Don't be shy.
我想我可能弄错了
I guess I was mistaken, kids.
很明显地，这里根本没有拟叶虫
There are obviously no leaf bugs in this area. Even if...
它们在我身上!
No, they're on me!
我好像吸到一只了!
I think I swallowed one!
汤米!把它抓出来!
Tommy! Pull it out!
好吧
Uh, okay.
哼哼叫的是只坏脾气的袋鼠
Then humpfing a '"humpf'" was a sour Kangaroo,
她自以为自己无所不知
the type who's convinced she knows better than you.
她制订规矩也执行法律
She made every law and enforced every rule
以努尔森林的领导者自居
as self-proclaimed head of the jungle of Nool.
为什么我不能和其他小孩玩？
Why can't I play with the other kids, Mom?
我说过，在丛林里
How many times have I told you that
言行绝不能像只野生动物
the jungle is no place to act like a wild animal.
那个叫荷顿的还真是个怪胎
My, that Horton certainly is eccentric.
孩子们从他身上学到很多东西
And the children are learning so much from him.
学会怎么变成一群愚蠢的笨蛋!
Learning to be a bunch of harebrained half-wits!
所以我的小袋鼠都由我亲自教育
And that's why my Rudy is pouch-schooled.
就在袋鼠妈妈冷嘲热讽的时候…
So while Kangaroo stood there, sneering a sneer...
荷顿，今天真是太精采了!
Horton, that was the best time I've ever had in my life!
你下次要带我们看什么？
What are you gonna show us next?
…那粒小灰尘再度飞过荷顿的耳旁
...once again, the speck floated right by Horton's ear.
他又听到一个极为细小的声音
Then he heard it again, just a very faint yelp,
听来像是个很小的生物在求救
as if some tiny person were calling for help.
你知道他怎么想吗？
And you know what he thought?
他认为在那一粒小小的微尘上
Why, he thought that there must be someone
一定有人!
on top of that small speck of dust!
或许是一家人，很有可能
Or even a family, it just might be so,
一个有几个孩子要养的家庭
a family with children just starting to grow.
我想活下去!
I want to live!
我先闪 了，凯蒂，换你接手!
I gotta go. Katie, you're in charge!
等一等!
Wait!
-回来! -小心点!
- Come back! - Watch it!
再一根!再一根!再一根!
One more! One more! One more!
-我听见有人靠近! -香蕉给我!
- I hear someone coming! - Give me those!
-等一等! -快拉警报!
- Wait! - Sound the alarm!
原谅我的大象腿!
Excuse me. Pardon my stampede!
抱歉，猴子家族 我等一下会来帮忙整理!
Sorry, Wickershams! I promise I'm gonna clean all this up later!
把弹药拿来!
Bring the ammo!
早晨的香蕉味让我心旷神怡
I love the smell of bananas in the morning.
香蕉炸弹发射!
Banana in the hole!
别这样!我们都是哺乳类耶!
Come on, guys! We're all mammals!
我想外交策略完全没用
I feel the diplomatic process is beginning to break down.
你在这里，我接住你了!
There you are! I got you!
你好，孩子们
Hi, kids!
好险
Wow.
好了
There.
这下你安全了
Now you're safe.
我确定我听到你说了些什么 我很确定
I know I heard you say something. I just know it.
你在哪里？
Where are you?
荷顿!
Horton!
对不起
Sorry!
都是这粒小灰尘啦! 它向我求救
I just... There was this speck, and it called out for help.
-我就… -这粒小灰尘向你求救？
- And I was... - The speck called out for help?
不是灰尘在求救啦，那太扯了
Well, not the speck. I mean, that's ridiculous.
你以为我是那个意思喔？ 灰尘怎么可能会求救
Is that what you thought I meant? No, the speck can't call out for help.
拜托，别闹了
Come on, get real.
是灰尘上的小小人需要我帮助
No, there's a tiny person on that speck that needs my help.
乱讲，根本没有那么小的人!
Absurd. There aren't people that small!
可能并不是他们小
Well, maybe they aren't small.
-也许是我们比较大 -荷顿
- Maybe we're big. - Horton.
仔细想想，要是真有人正在那上面
No, really, think about it. What if there was someone way out there
低头看着我们的世界
looking down on our world right now?
对他们来说，我们就是灰尘
And to them, we're the specks.
这时有人说
And then, maybe someone else will come along and say,
“根本没那么小的人” 第一个人就说
"Oh, there can't be people that small", and the first guy would say,
“你是说我说谎？”
"Are you calling me a liar?"
另一人就说：“敢说谎就要承认”
And the second guy would say, "If the shoe fits, wear it!"
接着两个人打了起来
And now the fists are flying, and the first guy picks up a brick,
接下来的对话小孩子不大适合听
and you might want to zip up the pouch for this next part.
“死胖子，你欠揍吗？”
"All right, fat boy, you want some of this..."
-荷顿! -怎样？
- Horton! - What?
那粒灰尘上什么都没有
There is nothing on that speck.
-可是我听到了 -你有吗？
- But I heard. - Did you?
真的？天哪
Really? Oh, my.
那为什么我什么也没听到？
Then how come I don't hear anything?
这个嘛…
Well...
看不到、听不到或感觉不到
If you can't see, hear or feel something,
那东西就绝对不存在
it doesn't exist.
还有相信那些幻想出来的小小人
And believing in tiny, imaginary people
在努尔森林这个地方
is just not something we do or tolerate,
是我们不该做，也不会容忍的事
here in the jungle of Nool.
是吗？可是我敢说只要我去试 我一定可以找到
Really? Because I bet if I really tried, I could find somebody who'd believe
-愿意相信的人 -你什么也不许做
- what I've been saying. - You will do nothing of the sort.
不准你对任何人说这无聊的谎言 特别是对小孩子
You will not breathe a word of this lie to anyone else, especially the children.
不准用这些谎言毒害他们的心灵
I do not want you poisoning their minds with this nonsense.
我们的社区可是有规范的，荷顿
Our community has standards, Horton.
如果你还想继续待下去 我劝你还是遵守规范
If you want to remain a part of it, I recommend you follow them.
祝你今天愉快
Have a nice day.
好吧，我会好好思考你说的话
All right, then, I'll take that under advisement.
十分感激你的建议
Certainly appreciate your input.
真搞不懂，我明明就有听到啊
I don't understand. I know I heard you.
声音很明显从我面前飘过去
It was as plain as the nose on my face.
对了，也许你听不到我
That's it. Maybe you can't hear me.
当然啦，你们的耳朵一定也很小 所以我要大声点
Of course! Your ears must be tiny. I need to speak up.
哈!
Hello!
有些动物…我想我知道有谁
Now some people out there, I think I know who,
或许也会认同刻薄的袋鼠妈妈
may find they agree with that sour Kangaroo.
认为不可能有跟虱子一样小的人
'"There can't really be people as small as a mite. '"
或许有可能…真的有… 因为荷顿说对了
Well, there can, and there are, because Horton was right.
哈!
Hello!
这一声“哈”一路传下来
That single '"hello'" traveled all the way down
进入灰尘，穿过了云层 直到传到了这座小镇
to the speck, through the clouds, until it found a small town.
这里叫呼呼镇，呼呼族就住这
A town known as Whoville, for there lived the Whos,
平安快乐过活，只知道好消息
feeling happy and safe, knowing only good news,
不知道自己的世界只是一粒灰尘
unaware that their world was a speck on a clover,
也没发现快乐的生活正面临危险
unaware that the sweet life they knew might be over.
-跳过! -钻过!
- Over! - Under!
呼呼镇的镇长名叫麦克当奈德
The Mayor of Whoville, a man named McDodd,
做事认真又正直，只是有点无厘头
was devoted and fair and a little bit odd.
镇长夫妇有一群孩子要照顾
The Mayor and his wife, they had children to spare,
九十六个女儿 有些坐在这里、有些坐在那里
96 daughters, some here and some there.
有九十六个女儿要爱 有九十六个女儿要教
96 girls to love, 96 girls to teach,
不过镇长只能给每个女儿几秒钟
but the Mayor had only a few seconds for each.
爸爸!我呼呼族历史考试满分
Daddy, I got better than best on my Who-story test.
呼呼族历史，我最熟了
Who-story. I remember it well.
真是我的好女儿
That's one of my girls.
-海达偷用我的梳子! -荷莉才偷用我的梳子!
- Hildy's been using my hairbrush! - Holly's been using my hairbrush!
快看那边!
Look! Over there!
好多了
There. All better.
能帮我买一支呼呼手机吗？ 我们班上每一个同学都有
Can I please have a Who-phone, Dad? Everyone else in my class has one.
是吗？每个都有？
Oh, really? Everyone?
我会好好考虑的
I will think about it.
爸，快看!爸，快看!
Daddy, look! Daddy, look!
牙“此”
Toof.
是牙“齿”，亲爱的，要陨
It's a "T-H", sweetheart. It's "tooth."
呼呼族的传统，和你我的不同
In Whoville tradition, unlike yours or mine,
他们镇长的职位由长子代代相传
the Mayor's oldest is next in the Mayoral line.
谁是长子？接下这家的棒子？
And who was the oldest? To lead and stand tall?
乔乔，他儿子，最矮小的一个
It was JoJo, his son, the smallest Who of all.
说吧，乔乔，你今天好不好？ 发生了什么事？有什么新闻？
So, JoJo, what's shaking? What's happening? What's the word?
相信现在你我都非常清楚
Now, to you or to me, it's abundantly clear
乔乔根本不想接他父亲的职务
that JoJo did not want his father's career.
只见镇长一情愿的构思计划
But the Mayor pressed forward, completely deluded,
乔乔却若有所思的坐在那里
while JoJo just sat there in silence and brooded.
乔乔!
Oh, JoJo!
-为什么他的时间比较长？ -不公平
- Hey, why does he get more time? - That's not fair.
儿子!
Son! Hey!
他为什么不说话呢？
And why didn't he speak?
我想他是怕说了会让他爸难过
Well, I think that the lad was afraid if he did, he might let down his dad.
你知道什么最正点吗？
You know what's awesome?
这些就很正点
This is awesome.
看看这些墙壁上的祖先肖像
Just look at the men and women hanging on these walls.
你，乖儿子 你是百年家族杰出菁英的一份子
You, my boy, are part of a family legacy that spans centuries.
知道吗？你爷爷曾是呼呼镇镇长
You know what? Your grandfather was Mayor of Whoville,
还有你的曾曾祖母，没有错
and your great-grandmother, that's right,
现在来看看这一路
all the way down to your
伟大的…伟大的…伟大的… 没那么伟大的
great-great-great-great-not-so-great-
伟大的…伟大的…伟大的 曾曾曾…
great-great-great-great-great-great- great-great-great-great-
祖父
grandfather.
我希望有一天能加入他们
Someday I hope to join them.
成为家族的伟大菁英之一
Be one of the greats.
我告诉你，乔乔 没有比当镇长更赞的了
I tell you, JoJo, there is nothing like being Mayor.
镇长能签署决议案 批准法条、核准预算
I get to sign resolutions, approve ordinances, submit budgets,
而且在美食嘉年华会上 超级大肉丸上坐的一定是镇长
and in the Edible Parade, I'm the one sitting on top of the giant meatball.
有一天坐在上面的也会是你
Someday, that can be you, too, JoJo.
有一天你也会别上镇长徽章
Someday you'll be the one wearing the Mayoral Crest.
你只要…你只需要…
You just... You just need to...
你懂我的意思吗？
You know what I mean?
好吧，聊天愉快
Okay. Good chat.
我很高兴我们谈了这么多
I'm glad that we had this talk
接下来我就讲给自己听吧，也好
that I'm continuing now by myself. Good.
好了，很舒服吧
There. That ought to be comfy.
不要放在心上，摩登 一点也不用担心
Nothing wrong with this, Morton. Nothing wrong with this.
只有你我和小灰尘，一起聊天
Just you, me and the speck, shooting the breeze.
我们同国的 高兴的话，还可以办个公投
We're a club. We're a group. We can take a vote on the issues.
也能搞秘密组织，维护世界和平
We can be a secret society that controls the balance of power in the world.
-荷顿 -谁都不能加入
- Horton. - And no one else can join,
除非他头戴怪帽
unless they wear funny hats.
荷顿，听好!
Listen, Horton!
我的兄弟摩登是当然会员
The Chair recognizes Brother Morton.
我很高兴你找到这个小灰尘
I am really happy you found this speck and all,
不过你最好不要让别人知道此事
but you might want to think about keeping it to yourself.
什么？为什么？
What? Why?
因为你对着一支花讲话 正常人不会这样
Well, you're talking to a clover. That doesn't look good.
你知道有问题的是谁？
You know what doesn't look good?
你的口气好像这灰尘完全不存在
You talking about the speck like the speck isn't even there.
人家可没有在你背后说你坏话
The speck never said anything bad about you.
不过这显现了你的幻想力很强
But, hey! Good luck with your illusion of superiority.
它爱怎么想我随便它 它只是一粒灰尘
You know, the speck can think anything it wants about me. It's a speck.
我知道你在不爽什么了
I see what's going on here.
摩登，不管我和这粒灰尘多要好
Morton, no matter how tight the speck and I get,
它永远也取代不了你
the speck could never replace you.
我以为我不用解释你就会明白
I'm only sad that I would have to explain that, at this point.
你真够朋友，荷顿 谢谢你的安慰
Well, that's awesome, Horton. That really helps.
别把秘密告诉别人
Just try to keep this to yourself.
待会儿见吧，别乱说话
I'll see you later. Try.
荷顿，你手上拿的是什么？
Hey, Horton! What you got there?
什么？哪有？
What? Nothing!
我们什么也没做啊!
We're not doing anything.
-我们没有…根本没人？ -“我们”是谁？
- We're totally alone. - Who's "we"?
什么？我们？我刚有说吗？
"We"? What? "We"? Did I say that? I just... Oh.
没，那样说就代表我和谁在一起
No, I would never say that, because that would imply that
不是只有一个人
I was with someone, and not alone.
我说真的，这绝对不能说出去
Okay, seriously, you can't tell anybody. I mean it.
要是这秘密被人发现 事情会变得非常非常糟
If anybody finds out about this, it could be very, very bad.
我也不大明白是为什么
I'm not sure why.
我们绝对不会说
We won't tell anyone.
要是我们说了 我们也会叫他们不要跟别人说
And if we do, we'll tell them not to tell anyone.
太好了
Perfect!
好，我本来正在洗澡
Okay, I'm taking a bath, right,
因为我的肤质偏干…
'cause my skin gets kind of dry and a little bit ashy.
当荷顿详细说明他如何找到灰尘
While Horton came clean about the speck that he'd found
与如何拯救它免于被淹没命运时
and how he had saved it when it nearly drowned,
镇长也正好准备出发去上班
the Mayor set off on his morning commute
虽然他发现好像有点怪怪的
and noticed things weren't quite the same on his route.
但是请别怪罪荷顿 他根本不知道，上面一个小碰撞…
But please don't blame Horton, for he didn't know that a small bump above...
…我就往水里跳下去
...and I dove in the water like this!
…会造成下面的大地震
...was a big bump below.
阿乔，不要太拼命了
Hey, Joe, don't work too hard.
豪华地宝又不会自己盖好
These luxury condos, they don't build themselves.
真的假的!它自己盖好了耶!
Hey, look at that! I guess they do build themselves.
好吧，那也没什么
Okay, that happened.
镇长知道他负责的工作 就是要报告每天发现的异状
Now, the Mayor knew it was his job to convey the unusual things
不过问题是
that he'd noticed that day, but there was one problem.
虽然他有强烈预感…
Though his will was strong...
-你迟到了 -麻烦你了，叶波小姐
- You're late. - Thank you, Miss Yelp.
…但是呼呼镇看来一切都很正常
...nothing in Whoville had ever gone wrong.
该有的我们都有
We have all that we need. We need all that we've got.
我们都爱呼呼镇，住了不想走
We like it in Whoville. We like it a lot!
大家都忙着准备 呼呼镇即将到来的百年庆
We're all very busy with the Who-Centennial coming up,
所以请遵照会议程序进行
so let's bring this meeting to order.
镇长先生，我想你有好消息要说
Mr. Mayor, I presume you have some good news for us.
好消息
Well, it's news.
是有个消息啦
我不知道这件事情 到底算是好消息还是坏消息
I don't know if we need to go labeling it "good" or "bad" or anything like that.
事情就是… 我发现镇上出现了一些怪现象
The thing is, I have noticed some odd goings-on in Whoville lately.
是好的怪现象吗？
Good "odd goings-on"?
这个嘛…地震、天上旋转的云
Well, you know, tremors, clouds swirling in the sky.
在我看来，为了安全起见
And it seems to me, just to be safe,
也许可以考虑延后呼呼镇百年庆
we might want to consider postponing the Who-Centennial.
考虑什么？
Consider what?
腌后虎虎百年青
Postponing the Who-Centennial.
什么？腌后虎虎百年青
What? Speak up, man!
大声一点!
延后呼呼镇百年庆!可以吗？
Postponing the Who-Centennial! All right?
全体镇民正忙着庆祝 呼呼镇百年来幸福和谐的日子
We are about to celebrate 100 years of Whoville happiness and harmony,
而你竟然想延后这场活动？
and you want to postpone the celebration?
要是呼呼镇不安全呢？
Well, what if Whoville's not safe?
呼呼镇从来没有出过差错
Nothing ever goes wrong in Whoville,
从前没有，未来也不会有 你这个乱七八糟的笨蛋
never has and never will, you blathering boob!
呼呼镇百年庆照计划进行
The Who-Centennial will proceed as planned!
镇长只是一时短路秀逗
The Mayor was merely being an idiot.
从现在起请记得笑口常开
It will be all smiles from now on.
噢!噢!会痛!
That hurt!
小姐，我的点阅率早破百万了
Girl, I got 15,000 friends already.
什么叫照片不像？
What? What do you mean, it don't look like me?
那照片绝对是我! 十年前的我，等等，你先别挂
That looks just like me 10 years ago. Wait a minute. Hold on for a second.
居然说我是笨蛋，我才不是笨蛋
Treats me like an idiot. I am not an idiot.
我看起来像笨蛋吗？
Do I look like an idiot?
-你不会想听到答案的 -我不是笨蛋
- You don't want me to answer that. - I am not an idiot.
竟敢叫我笨蛋？ 我不会骂人是笨蛋
Has the nerve to call me a boob? I would never call somebody a boob.
他才是笨蛋，你看看你
He's a boob! Look at you.
恶心!
Yuck!
看到你那张脸
Look at your face.
我让你尝尝被叮满头包的滋味
And I bet you don't look so good with a stapler in your head!
哗!哗
Whoa! Whoa.
-谢了，叶波小姐 -别客气
- Thank you, Miss Yelp. - You're welcome.
哈？
Hello?
走开!不然我揍扁你!
Who said that? Back off! I'll punch you!
哈？
Hello?
哈
Hello.
你是谁啊？
Who's there?
我是镇长
This is the Mayor.
镇长？镇长!
The Mayor? The Mayor!
我在跟镇长说话耶!
I'm talking to the Mayor!
我就知道 我就知道有人住在这粒灰尘里
I knew it. I knew it. I knew it. I knew there was life on this speck.
灰尘？什么灰尘啊？
"This speck"? What speck?
我不大知道该怎么告诉你，但是…
Well, I don't exactly know how to tell you this, but...
你住在一粒灰尘里
You're living on a speck.
不是我想吐你槽啦! 排水管里的老兄
Well, I hate to disagree with you, O voice from the drainpipe,
但是我住在呼呼镇
but I live in Whoville.
那呼呼镇就是一粒灰尘
Well, then, Whoville's a speck.
才怪
Right.
不要闹了，你到底是谁？
Okay, seriously, who is this?
你是会计部的伯特？
Is this Burt from accounting?
错，我叫荷顿，我是只大象
No. This is Horton. I'm an elephant.
好吧，荷顿
Okay, "Horton."
真爱演，你在哪啊？
Fake name. Where are you?
从你站的位置来看 我猜我是…在天空上吧？
Well, from where you're standing, I guess I'm in the sky.
跟你比起来，我超大的
Compared to you, I'm enormous.
不过我已经瘦了很多
Which is saying something, because I've slimmed down quite a bit.
我游泳
I swim.
你的世界就在我们的一朵花上
Your whole world fits on a flower in my world.
伯特，你讲的冷笑话比我还冷
Oh, man, this is even pushing it for you, Burt.
看我把你放在阴影下会怎样？
Don't believe me? Watch what happens when I put you in the shade.
根本就不会怎样…
This is absolutely impossible...
天黑
Dark.
天亮
Light.
天黑
Dark.
天亮、天黑、天亮、天黑
Light. Dark, light, dark, light, dark, light, dark.
天亮
Light!
看到没？
Don't you see?
我们在神奇的机缘巧合中相遇
We're in the middle of some kind of amazing cosmic convergence.
两个完全不同的世界 出乎意料交会在一起
Two vastly different worlds, miraculously crossing paths!
我这边有够大，你那边有够小
Mine, colossal! Yours, miniscule.
而我们居然能搭上线
Yet somehow we've managed to make contact.
仔细想想，这真的很神奇
If you think about it, it's pretty amazing.
你们那边都没事吧？
Is everything okay down there?
你说咧？我们的世界在你手上!
I don't know. You tell me. You're the one holding the speck.
你们的世界在我手上
I'm the one holding the speck.
你不用担心，镇长先生
Don't you worry, Mr. Mayor.
先等我一下
Hold, please!
这是怎么回事？镇长一头雾水
What did all of this mean? The Mayor hadn't a clue.
所以他跑进拉鲁博士的办公室 她是呼呼大学里最聪明的博士
So he ran to the office of Dr. Larue, the brainiest brain on the staff at Who U.
拉鲁博士!
Dr. Larue!
我大概是疯了
This is crazy.
镇长先生
Mr. Mayor.
有什么需要我服务吗？
How may I be of assistance?
我不知道，我想问你一件事
I don't know. Hey, you know, I was just wondering
如果我们的世界 是一粒飘在空中的小灰尘
if our world were, say, a tiny speck floating through space,
我们怎么知道？
how would we know?
为什么你会问这种问题？
Well, why would you ask something like that?
没事，我都忘记我问什么了
No reason. No reason at all. I don't even remember.
对，我是问了
Yes, I do. You know what?
其实是有人告诉我的
Some guy was talking to me.
不是什么天空里的大象，是邻居
Not an elephant in the sky. A guy on the ground.
本来就有成千上万种可能
There would be several ramifications.
是好的“可能”吗？
Good ramifications?
一粒小灰尘？
A tiny speck?
对，小灰尘
Yeah. Tiny speck.
飘来飘去
Floating around.
最近是有一些无预警的地震 气候上也有不寻常的变化
Well, we'd have inexplicable tremors, dramatic changes in the weather,
如果我们没办法稳定这个世界
and if we didn't eventually achieve some sort of stability,
我们可能就会面临…世界末日!
our world would be destroyed!
世界末日？世界末日
Destroyed? Destroyed. Oh, destroyed.
荷顿!
Horton!
不，我是…阿宝
No, this is Benny.
荷顿他现在正在忙
Horton is busy right now.
开玩笑的啦!
No. I'm joking.
我在这
That's me.
我们完了
We're doomed.
荷顿，我想我需要你帮点小忙
Listen, Horton, turns out I need your help a little bit.
很明显地，要是这粒小灰尘乱飞
Apparently, if that speck keeps moving around,
我们的世界可能就会毁灭
our whole world could be obliterated.
所以我需要你帮我们找一个 更安全更稳定的新家
So I need you to find us Whos a safer, more stable home,
要快
and fast.
没问题，镇长先生，我看看…
No problem, Mr. Mayor. Let's see...
那里视野真好
Wow, that's a nice view.
一切都没问题吧？
Hello. Is everything okay?
上面怎么了？
What's going on up there?
这里简直是生死一瞬间现场版!
This entire jungle is a house of death!
等等，那里看来不错
Oh, wait. There's a good spot.
就在此时，荷顿看到努尔山顶
And it's then Horton saw at the top of Mount Nool,
有个看来宁静祥和又酷的小山洞
a small cave that looked peaceful and quiet and cool,
一朵向日葵高高盛开在洞穴里
where a sunflower grew proud and tall from the ground.
他知道呼呼族到了那里 绝对会平安无事
There, he knew every Who would be safe, would be sound.
我找到了，镇长，最完美的地点
I found it, Mayor. The perfect place.
就在那上面
Right up there,
-那座山顶上 -镇长先生
- on the top of Mount Nool. - Mr. Mayor?
我希望你能…
I wish you could...
亮晶晶
Shiny.
呼呼镇百年庆委员会正在等你
The Who-Centennial Committee is waiting for you
勘验美食游行要用的超级肉丸
to look over the giant meatball for the Edible Parade.
接着你要找牙医做呼呼根管治疗
And then you're due at the dentist for your Who-root canal.
在根管治疗前加上呼呼的名号 治疗时并不会比较舒服
You know, sticking "Who" in front of everything doesn't make it hurt less.
那是浪费时间
Just wastes time!
我才不要去
I don't want to go.
荷顿，我先走了
Listen, Horton, I've gotta go.
我得先去处理那颗超级大肉丸
Apparently, there's a problem with the giant meatball.
您尽管去处理那颗肉丸吧 这件特殊的任务就交给我
You just take care of that meatball, sir, and leave the freaking out to me.
荷顿展开危机重重的长途旅程
So then Horton began his long, perilous trek,
他决心拯救灰尘上的小小世界
determined to save the small world on the speck.
荷顿抱着坚定信念与仁慈的心
Horton was faithful and stalwart and kind.
我抓好你了
I got you.
他是无惧的勇士…
He was a brave hero...
我会保护你
I'll protect you!
…至少他心里是这么想的
...at least in his mind.
我们得小心谨慎，悄悄的前进
We must become invisible. Travel silently.
因为敌人搞不好正要暗算我们
For there are forces that would seek to destroy us.
(尖叫)
你以为你偷袭得了我？
So you think you can sneak up on me, huh?
显然你的功夫跟我差远了
It is clear that you are no match for my technique.
(痛)
你还真会用暗器来偷袭啊 看我的前空翻!
I see you have mastered the way of the snapping branch. Watch me tumble!
飞天鼠摩登!
Morton Mouse, go!
荷顿，真俐落 可是袋鼠妈妈有猴子军团
You are fast, Horton, but the Kangaroo has monkeys.
我会好好教训这群臭猴子 这是我们的使命
I will make monkeys of these monkeys. It is their destiny.
象派气功!
More clover!
荷顿是全世界最伟大的英雄!
Horton is the greatest hero of them all!
-荷顿! -摩登!
- Horton! - Morton!
上!
Go!
但是努尔山在那边
But Mount Nool is that way.
朝努尔山顶前进!快如闪 电!
To the top of Mount Nool! As fast as lightning! Away, I go.
抱歉，小家伙
Sorry, little fellow.
你不会有事的 只要专心冥想自己恢复健康
You'll be fine. Just think healing thoughts.
-荷顿!荷顿! -荷顿!你看，你看!
- Horton! Look! - Horton! Look, look, look!
我们全都有载着小世界的苜蓿花
We've all got our own clovers with worlds on them!
对
Yeah.
我的小世界里，全部都是迷你马
In my world, everyone's a pony,
他们都吃彩虹，然后便便是蝴蝶
and they all eat rainbows and poop butterflies.
那真是太赞了，凯蒂
That's beautiful, Katie.
虽然有点怪怪的
In a really weird way.
我的世界叫洁西卡王国 大家都超崇拜洁西卡女王
My world is called Jessica-land, and everyone worships Queen Jessica
因为洁西卡很漂亮
because Jessica is so beautiful.
洁西卡，那听起来棒呆了
Jessica, that was awesome.
-路迪! -小心点!
- Rudy! - Mom, be careful!
我好朋友席克住那上面
My best friend Thidwick lives on that.
路迪，没人住在这上面 这是不可能的
Rudy, no one lives on this. It's not possible.
那个荷顿真可恶
That Horton is a menace.
妈!拜托，别这样
Mom, Mom! Please, you're so weird. Don't do this to me.
给我进房去
Honey, go to your room.
荷顿!
Horton!
射门得分!
It's good!
你到底在干嘛？
What do you think you're doing?
你们有大麻烦了!
You guys with worlds are in trouble!
-你忘了我们之前讨论过什么？ -记得，我是大象
- Have you forgotten what we discussed? - Oh, no. I'm an elephant,
大象从不忘记，这是个诅咒!
and elephants never forget. It's a curse, really.
我记得你哼了一声
I remember I was on my head, and you said "Humpf,"
我抬头看你，然后你说 “你到底在干麻？”
and I looked up, and you said, "What are you doing?"
我说了灰尘的事
And I said the thing about the speck.
你拉我耳朵，又戳我的额头…
Then you pulled my ears and you poked me in the forehead...
-荷顿! -没错，你动手了
- Horton! - Well, you did.
把那朵苜蓿花给我，马上给!
Give me that clover, Horton. Now!
不要
No.
不要？
No?
对
Yeah.
你确定你要跟我作对？
Are you sure you want to fight this fight, Horton?
我可以跟你保证 到时候场面一定很难看
Because I promise you it will get very ugly, very fast.
没多久你就会开始问自己
And you need to ask yourself,
我干嘛要把自己搞成这样？
"Do I really want to put myself through all this?
“就为了一朵苜蓿花？”
"For a clover?"
注意听我说，荷顿
Take it from me, Horton.
你没注意听
You don't.
快把它交出来!
So hand it over!
不要!我不能把它给你
No! I can't give it to you.
这粒灰尘上有住人
There are people on this speck.
虽然他们个子非常小
Granted, they're very small people,
但万物生而平等 不论他们有多渺小
but a person's a person, no matter how small.
你太离谱了，荷顿 我会让你付出代价的
You just crossed the line, Horton, and I'm gonna make you pay.
那个荷顿太危险了
That Horton is a menace.
他害这群孩子整天胡思乱想
He has those kids using their imaginations.
太可恶了
It's sick.
好吧!我得快点把这粒灰尘 放到山顶去，要“快马加鞭”
All right, I gotta get this speck up to the top of Mount Nool, ASAP,
虽然我不是马 但人家说飞象也能过河
whatever that means. Probably, "Act Swiftly, Awesome Pachyderm."
那有什么困难的？
I mean, how hard can that be?
只不过是条…保证摔死大象的桥
It's just a straight plummet to certain death.
这看起来有点…不太坚固
This looks kind of precarious.
先不要吓自己
Well, no need to worry.
他们当初建这条桥的时候
Obviously, when they build a bridge like this,
一定有想过有一天会有大象走过
they take into account that elephants will be crossing here.
很好，还不错 我就稍微给它…试试看!
All right. Feels good. I'll just get the feel of it!
勇气
That's true.
没错
噢，天啊
Oh, God.
你好，今天好吗，镇长先生？
Hello. And how are we today, Mr. Mayor?
说：“啊”
Say, "Ah."
请漱漱口
Rinse, please.
这里有些木板也早该换了吧
I think a few of these boards could stand to be replaced.
我要想像我很轻 我轻得像…羽毛
I just need to think light. I'm light as a feather.
轻飘飘的…羽毛!
I'm light as a feather!
好重的羽毛
Heavy feather.
这针只会有一点点痛
Okay, this will just pinch a little.
我得比羽毛还轻 有什么比羽毛还轻？
I'm lighter than a feather. What's lighter than a feather?
空气!没有比它轻的了 所以这就表示
Air! There's nothing lighter. So it stands to reason
只要我吸入愈多空气
that the more air I have,
我就能…变更轻
the lighter I'll be.
下一位，请进
Next, please.
真是吓死人了
All right, that was absolutely terrifying.
现在我得把自已拉上去
If I just pull myself up!
不要太紧张
Try not to panic.
刚刚差一点就锉起来
That could've been a disaster.
“脚踏实地”的感觉还真棒 让我有股想跳舞的冲动
Wow. I feel really good right now. Maybe it's my new sense of purpose.
没事了
All right.
乔乔!我需要你帮忙，有空吗？
Hey, JoJo! I need your help. Can you help me?
很好 首先，你先去姐妹们的房间
Okay, great. Okay. First, I need you to go to the girls' room.
把汉娜的陶瓷娃娃拿下来
Take down Hanna's china doll collection and then...
别盯着我的手看
Stop looking at my arm.
再把荷莉L集的灯泡收好
Put away Holly's light bulb collection, and then...
把容易坏或容易碎的东西全收好
You know what? Just take care of anything that might break or shatter.
好吧，我就让你一次看个够
Okay, take a good long look.
看够了吧？谢啦!儿子
Got it? Thanks, JoJo!
这些…还有那个…
Here. And... Take that. And...
老公，今天比较晚喔
Hi. You're home late.
抱歉老婆，我刚是去牙医那里 处理我的…手
Sorry, hon. I was just having some dental work done on my arm.
发生什么…
So, what was...
奈德!
Ned!
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
你指的是？
What do you mean?
我不是侦探，不过你煸诘醯粕
Well, I'm no detective, Ned, but you are hanging from the chandelier.
我只是想把它移远一点
I just thought it might look better
免得我们晚上睡觉时被砸到
somewhere it can't fall on us and crush us in our sleep.
到底怎么回事？
What is going on?
老婆
Hey, hon,
你有没有过一种感觉 好像有人盯你看？
did you ever get the feeling that you were being watched?
对啊，我想是有吧
Yeah, sure. I suppose.
要是你知道一直盯着你看的那家伙
And then you get the feeling that maybe that thing watching you is
是只…超大的大象呢？
a giant elephant?
要是有人跟你说你的世界
And you know how you get that weird feeling
居然是在一粒小灰尘上呢？
that your world is actually a tiny speck?
而我刚才提到的那只大象 它把灰尘放一朵花上
And that the elephant that I talked about earlier is carrying it around on a flower.
虽然你很清楚你要是说出来 大家一定会认为你疯了
And you realize that if you tell anybody, they'd think you were crazy.
但你还是觉得 你有责任保障大家的安全
But you still feel a responsibility to keep everyone safe.
你知道那种感觉吗？
You know that feeling?
我想我应该不知道
You know, I'm gonna have to say no.
你知道那种感觉吗？
Do you know that feeling?
才不咧
No.
真累，我想我该上床睡觉了
Yawn. Wow. I am beat. Time to hit the hay, I guess.
亲爱的，我知道你最近压力很大
Sweetheart, I know you're under a lot of stress,
所以就算你看到了大象和几朵花 那也不错啊
and if you're seeing elephants and flowers, then fine.
只是不要把这些事告诉别人
Just don't tell anyone else that story, okay?
别忘了，这并不是世界末日
And remember, it's not the end of the world.
“世界末日”
"The end of the world."
呼叫镇长，听到请回答，完毕
Horton to Mayor. Horton to Mayor. Come in, Mayor. Over.
荷顿？
Horton?
我这里收讯不太好
I get terrible reception here.
这样呢？我用力喊，你听得到吗？
How about this? If I get up real close, can you read me?
有!收到了
Yep! Roger that.
我们到安全的地方了吗？
Are we at that safe place yet?
就快到了 我想最困难的关卡已经过了
Almost. I'm pretty sure the worst part's over.
这是大象荷顿的报告
This is your elephant speaking.
我将带各位前往努尔山 请好好享受这趟旅程
Just sit back, enjoy the ride, and we'll have you to Mount Nool in no time.
不行，不能拿冰淇淋当早餐
No, you can't have ice cream for breakfast.
-拜托 -拜托
- Please. - Please.
那是谁？
Who's that?
那里还有别人吗？
Is there someone else there?
那是我太太…还有小孩
Well, that's my wife and kids.
你还有家人
You have a family.
没错，我有个漂亮老婆 九十六个女儿，还有一个儿子
I do, indeed. A beautiful wife, 96 daughters, and one son.
你还真行啊
Oh, busy guy.
我们还共用一间厕所，你懂吧
And we all share one bathroom. You know how that is.
当然，共用厕所嘛!
Yeah. Don't I know it.
厕所？
Bathroom?
-奈德! -什么？
- Ned! - What?
亲爱的，你知道你在屋顶上吧？
Sweetheart, you know you're on the roof, right?
-拜托，妈妈 -什么？
- Please, Mom. - What's that?
不行，快上床睡觉 爸爸今天精神不好
No, you need to go to bed. Daddy's having a breakdown.
奈德，你现在又怎样了？
Ned, what are you up to now?
我正打算下去哄孩子睡觉
I was just about to put the kids to bed when I got off the roof.
事情就是这样，没错
And that's what happened. Right.
-爸爸？ -什么？
- Daddy? - Yes.
-你能不能帮我倒杯水？ -没问题
- Can I have a glass of water? - Of course.
-我也要 -我也要
- Me, too. - Me, three.
我也要
Me, 28.
好吧
Okay.
乔乔!
Hey, JoJo!
好多好多杯水啊 还遇见我想要遇见的人
A lot of liquid. A lot of liquid. Just the person I wanted to see.
最近我们父子意见总是相左
Yeah, I realize that we have not been seeing eye-to-eye lately,
大部份都是我不对
and most of it is my fault.
没错
It's true.
我一直都一意孤行
You know what I've been trying to do?
要你照我的想法去规划你的未来
I have been trying to impose my vision of your future on you.
让我好好跟你解释清楚
Let me make this perfectly clear.
乔乔，你想当什么样的镇长都行
JoJo, you can be whatever kind of Mayor you want to be.
积极、稳重、直率 哪一种都行
Hands-on, strong and silent, outspoken, it's up to you.
很好，我感觉好多了
Well, good. I feel so much better.
我期待看到你有所成就，儿子
I am expecting big things from you, young man. Big things.
晚安
All right. Good night.
很好，就这样
Good stuff. Good talk.
接着乔乔溜出去，他孤单又难过
Then JoJo snuck out, feeling lonely and sad,
难过父亲竟然这么不了解自己
and tragically misunderstood by his dad.
他这么晚了要去哪里呢？
And where was he going at such a late hour?
他跑到呼呼镇废弃弃的天文台上头
Up to Whoville's abandoned Star-Studying Tower,
这里让他感到自在又满足
a place where the boy felt contented, free.
这里让他能随心所欲
A place he could be what he wanted to be.
那里头有什么，先让我卖个关子
And what was inside there, I'd say if I could.
But up above, the Kangaroo was up to no good.
这时在外头 袋鼠妈妈正在进行邪恶的计划
我可以出来吗？
Can I come out now, Mom?
不行，路迪，待在你的房间里
No, Rudy. Stay in your room.
-但是… -在里头待好
- But, Mom... - Stay inside.
维拉考夫先生
Mr. Vladikoff?
吃饭，滚
Eating. Go.
我知道你在吃大餐 但是我需要你帮忙
Yes, I realize you're busy, but I need your help.
那个荷顿
It's Horton.
他最近被一朵苜蓿给迷昏了
He's become obsessed with a clover.
他还幻想那上面有住人
And he actually thinks there are little people on it.
我要你把苜蓿给做了
I want that clover destroyed.
小事，杀鸡需要用牛刀吗？ 你自己动手吧
Sure. What a big deal this is for you, bro.
我本来想自己动手 但身为贵妇，我才不想弄脏手
I'd do it myself, but being a lady, I prefer not to get my hands dirty.
不过我听说你从不嫌手脏
But I hear you have no problem with that.
对
No.
没问题，简单得很
No problem. Easy peazy.
但那也得看你的诚意
But I will only do this for a price.
最起码要给我一对全新的…
In exchange for a brand new pair of...
不
No.
我要这只小袋鼠
This little kangaroo.
-妈! -安静，妈咪正在想事情
- Mom! - Quiet, Rudy. Mommy's thinking it over.
谢了，经过我仔细考虑
Well, thanks, but on second thought,
我还是找猴子军团
I think I'm going to have the Wickersham brothers
帮忙好了
take care of this for me.
很好，找他们，他们人多势众
Yeah, of course, Wickersham. I mean, they're a classy operation.
不!你不能找他们!
You know, they do... Wait! No! You can't go with Wickersham!
不、不、不… 这件事让猴子们来处理最适合
No, no, no, the Wickershams would be perfect for this job.
那群笨猴子，连吓都吓不死人
But they're monkeys! Is not scary!
还是谢谢你，下次再说吧
Thanks, anyway. Maybe next time.
等等!
Wait!
我会这样对付那朵苜蓿花
Here is what I will do to precious clover.
先逮住它，然后压扁它
I will take it, I will crush it,
最后再一口吞掉它
and I will devour it.
这比想像的大
Bigger than it look.
等一下!
One second.
我的妈呀!
Holy moly.
先等一等
Hang on.
之后我再把它吐出来
Then I regurgitate it.
然后我会再把它给吞下去!
Then I'm going to devour it second time!
所以总共是吞了两次
So, two times devoured.
听起来不错 但是我想先找猴子们谈谈
Sounds nice, but I think I'll talk to the Wickershams.
等等!
Wait!
现在刚好在做促销
Here is best part.
我愿意…免费奉送
I do all gratis.
这可是免费的
That's free, bro.
你觉得如何？
What do you think?
成交
Deal.
好耶!搞定，感谢你 这次是做口碑的
Yes! Score. Thanking you. You won't regret.
镇长!
Mayor!
快开门，镇长先生!
Open up, Mr. Mayor! Mr. Mayor!
下雪了!现在是夏天!
It's snowing! In the summer!
没错，真的下雪了
Yes. Yes, it is.
气候出现戏剧性的变化
It's a dramatic change in the weather,
我们就像一粒空中的小灰尘
as if we were a speck, floating through space.
我不知道你是怎么知道的 但全被你说中了
I don't know how you knew, but somehow you did,
现在呼呼镇即将面临一场大灾难
and Whoville is headed for disaster.
天哪，荷顿
Horton.
什么？
What?
没事，我来处理
Nothing. I'm on it.
该是我们拯救呼呼镇的时候了
It's up to us to save the people of Whoville.
你们虽然还小，但人很多耶!
You're small, but there are a lot of you!
真是的
That's it.
好了，后面还有吗？
Okay, anybody else?
很好
Good.
这不好玩，这是末日的征兆!
No, no. No enjoyment. This is not fun. It is a sign of doom!
亲爱的，真是…
Aw, sweetie, that's...
不!危险!危险!
No, no, no! Danger! Danger!
立刻停止一切玩乐的行为!
Stop having fun immediately!
这样真的很危险!
This is dangerous! Okay!
停止!
Stop it!
荷顿!
Horton!
镇长
Hey, Mayor.
代志大条了啦
We're in big trouble down here.
夏天才过一半居然下雪了
It's happening! It's snowing in the middle of summer.
世界末日到了!
It's the end of the world!
等等，我大概知道问题出在哪里
Hold on, Mayor. I think I know what your problem is.
现在好一点没？
There. That better?
效果还蛮不错的
That seems to have worked.
好像有花生的味道？
Do I smell peanuts?
对，那是我最爱吃的点心 但味道会散不掉
Yeah, they're my favorite snack, but they tend to linger.
鱼宝宝，不!
Finwick, no!
等一下，镇长先生 我想有人来找碴了
Hang on, Mr. Mayor. I may have to put up a fight.
一只受惊的大象是很恐怖的
A frightened elephant can be very dangerous!
这可是你自己找的喔，老兄!
All right! You've called down the thunder, buddy!
想找碴？我可是加足马力了! 有种来吧!
You hungry for trouble? I'm an "All you can eat" salad bar! Take a bite!
我讨厌跑步
I hate running.
摩登!
Morton!
不要吓我
Don't do that.
荷顿!
Horton!
荷顿!你在这里!
Horton! There you are!
有麻烦了!你有听说吗？
We got trouble! Wait, stay, wait! Did you hear that?
不，听我说 袋鼠妈妈，已经发疯，脑袋坏了
No, I'm here, okay. Listen. No! Go! Kangaroo has gone nuts, bananas.
她告诉大家要把你踢出努尔森林
She's telling everyone that you should be kicked out of Nool.
她那样说？我还以为我们是朋友
She said that? I thought we were her friends.
听说她去找了维拉!
Word is she's gone to Vlad!
我认识两个维拉
Vlad? Vlad? I know two Vlads.
是那个坏的维拉 还是会烤饼干的兔子维拉？
Is it the bad Vlad or the bunny Vlad that makes the cookies?
她最好是会派兔子送饼干给你
Yeah, Horton, she's sending you a bunny with cookies.
用膝盖想也知道是坏的维拉
I think we can assume it's the bad Vlad.
对，那样才合理
Yeah, that's a good call.
所以除非你能忍受 那双心狠手辣凶残的臭爪子
So unless you're cool with giant, razor-sharp claws
把你的身体撕成碎片… 快把花给丢掉吧
ripping the flesh off your body, I'd get rid of the clover!
不可以!我答应过镇长
I can't! I promised the Mayor.
我说到做到…做不到就不说
I meant what I said, and I said what I meant,
我们大象的忠诚度是百分百
and an elephant's faithful, 100%.
拜托，为了我，就这么一次 忠诚度做到九十九分就好了
Please. For me, just this once. Be faithful 99% of the time.
我从来没拿过九十九分 但我还是很棒的!
I've never gotten 99% on anything, and I think I'm awesome! So, come on!
我遵守承诺，一言既出驷马难…
I meant what I said, and I said what I meant.
那我就不追了
I'm not gonna say it.
不过你瞎忙一整天也没用
You can do that all day, it's not happening.
大象的忠诚…
An elephant's faithful, 100%.
没错，那是我的原则、座右铭 谢谢你提醒我
That's right. That's my code, my motto. But thanks for the warning.
座右铭，好吧
Motto. Okay.
但是要留意天上
But watch the skies.
一定要紧盯着天空!
Keep watching the skies!
镇长，快通知所有人躲好
Mayor, you need to get everyone underground.
快!
Now!
我并不想发出警报
I don't want to sound the alarm,
但我们极有可能会遭到一只
but there's a good possibility we may be attacked
-大型肉食性鸟类攻击 -什么？
- by a giant carnivorous bird. - What?
也有可能是会遇上送饼干的兔子 但我想机会不大
There's a small chance it could be a bunny with cookies, but I wouldn't count on it.
那真是太可怕了
They are formidable.
镇长，你在吗？
Mayor? Are you there?
在，那真是个好主意，只是…
Yeah. No. That's a great idea. It's just...
如果要让大家动起来 我必须取得镇议会批准
In order to get everyone mobilized, I'd need the okay of the City Council,
但他们从不肯听我说
and they never listen to me.
他们还叫我笨蛋!
I've been called a boob,
叫了好几次，我办不到!
several times. I can't do it!
你必须警告他们，镇长!
You have to talk to them, Mayor! Okay. Listen.
坏的维拉!
Bad Vlad!
那绝对不是送饼干的兔子
That is definitely not a bunny.
甩掉他了 我想甩掉他，就甩掉他了
Lost him. Meant to lose him, and I lost him. Good.
这树真碍事!
Is this tree for real? Come on!
抓紧了呼呼镇!这下麻烦大了!
Hang on, Whoville! This is gonna get rough!
准备好受死吧!
Now you're going to get it!
让你见识一下高手!
Get ready for the best!
离我远一点!
Leave me alone!
荷顿!
Horton!
他一定会从某个地方跳出来
I just know he's gonna jump out somewhere.
哈
Hello.
投降吧
Chess mate.
现在让我把苜蓿花拿过来
Now it's time for me to take clover
毁了上面所有的小小人…
and crush all the little people on it, who are saying...
抱歉，我们先从这里下去了
Sorry. This is where we get off.
鼻子歪了啦!
Right in the beak!
漂亮!我的头脑还真灵光
Cool line. Usually I can't think of those things till later.
-镇长 -荷顿
- Mayor? - Horton.
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
还好，怎么回事？那鸟呢？
Well, more or less. What happened? The bird?
他啊，他居然攻击我 镇长，你的镇民现在有危险
Yeah, it attacked me. Mayor, your people are in danger.
我打算这么做
You know what? I'm gonna do it.
我要告诉大家发生了什么事
I'm going to go out there and tell them what is going on.
太好了! 快，事不宜迟
Perfect. Now, quick. Get going.
镇长先生!不太对劲啊!
Hey! Mr. Mayor! Something's wrong!
-我的地下室变成阁楼了 -科学博物馆全毁了
- My basement's in the attic. - The Science Museum is history.
-失物招领处不见了 -到底怎么了，镇长先生？
- The lost and found is missing. - What's going on, Mr. Mayor?
我要宣布进入紧急状态
I'm declaring a state of emergency!
没事的!别担心!
Don't worry! Don't worry!
镇长他只是在耍白痴
The Mayor is just being a moron.
等等，呼呼镇现在非常危险
No, wait! Whoville is in terrible danger!
所有人都该立刻躲进地下室避难
Everyone needs to get down to the underground storage area immediately.
好吧!好吧!
Fine! Fine!
我们就用民主的方式解决
Let's do this democratically.
有谁希望看到呼呼镇 伟大光荣的百年庆
Who wants the joy and glory and festivity
照计划进行？
of the Who-Centennial to proceed as planned?
好耶!
Yeah!
又有谁和镇长一样
And who, like the Mayor,
认为最好能在黑漆漆的地下室里
thinks it would be better to spend the Who-Centennial
度过呼呼镇百年庆呢？
in an underground storage area?
好耶!
Yeah!
等等，大家听我说
Wait! You've gotta listen to me!
我们的世界可能会爆炸毁灭
Our whole world could explode!
比这快多了
Much more quickly!
也不会发出这种怪声
And our world wouldn't make that noise.
人民已经作了决定，镇长先生
The people have spoken, Mr. Mayor.
你已经完蛋了，没有人相信你
You're finished. No one believes you.
也没人支持你
No one supports you.
荷顿就相信我
Horton believes me.
荷顿？
Horton?
谁是荷顿？
Who's Horton?
荷顿是…在天上的一只大象
Horton is a giant elephant in the sky!
不用找了，他是隐形的
Don't bother looking, he's invisible.
他正冒着生命危险拯救我们
And he's the one risking his life to get Whoville,
让落在花朵上小灰尘里的呼呼镇 得到安全
which, by the way, is a speck on a clover, to safety!
我可以证明
I can prove it!
荷顿的声音会从这喇叭传出来
Horton's voice comes out of this horn.
荷顿!
Horton!
我已召集所有人民到广场集合
I have all the Whos gathered in town square!
让他们听听你的声音
Let them know you're there!
天，原来当公众人物压力这么大
Gee. This is kind of a high-pressure situation, then.
我还真不知道该说什么
Wow. I am really drawing a blank here.
我知道了
I know!
荷顿
Horton!
荷顿，快点啊!
Horton, we're waiting!
是时候该向大家证明你的存在
Time to show everyone that you exist,
顺便说明白…我绝对不是笨蛋
and by extension, what a non-boob I am.
等等!
Wait!
大家看那个风 你们以为那代表了什么？
Everyone, look at the wind. What do you think that that means?
那是代表…
It means...
那很明显地是代表…
It means, obviously...
放风筝大赛现在开始
Let the kite-flying race begin!
看看你有多丢脸，荷顿
What a burn on you, Horton!
啊…有够冰的
Brain freeze.
把花还给我
Give me back my speck!
就差一点，可惜
Not this time, guy.
我真的很抱歉让你失望 但是这比我自己重要多了
I am so sorry that I let you down, but this... This is bigger than me.
带孩子们找个安全的地方躲好
Get the family together and get somewhere safe.
我会的!我相信你
I will! I believe you.
这下看你怎么玩，大笨象
I've got you now, elephant.
不要丢…不要!
No, no, no!
不
Oh, no!
镇长？
Mayor?
有人在家吗？
Anybody there?
哈？
Hello?
有人吗？
Anyone?
荷顿他找过了一朵又一朵
But clover by clover by clover, he found
却怎么也找不到他要找的那一朵
that the one he sought for was just not around.
镇长？
Mayor?
哈？
Hello?
直到中午，可怜的荷顿精疲力尽
And by noon, poor Horton, more dead than alive,
他找过的九千零五朵花 已堆成许多花堆
had picked, searched and piled up 9,005.
哈？
Hello?
抱歉打扰到你了
Sorry to bother you,
没人
nobody.
敲敲门
Knock, knock.
这时候你该说 系“象”啦？
This is where you'd say, "Who's there?"
如果你在的话
If there were any Whos there.
听懂没？系“象”啦!
Get it? "Whos there."
他整天不停的找
All day he looked, looked on and on,
直到他已几乎放弃希望
until his hope was almost gone.
不…拜托，不要!
No, no, no! Please, no!
这样不公平啦!
This isn't fair!
等一下，难道会是这一朵吗？
But, wait, could this one be the one?
他千辛万苦要找的就是这朵？
Was all his searching finally done?
是的，皇天不负苦心人
Ah, yes, for this was the hour.
荷顿终于找到了 就在这三百多万朵花之中
Horton had found them on the three millionth flower.
镇长!镇长!
Mayor! Mayor!
我找到你了!
I found you!
镇长？
Mayor?
你在吗？
Are you there?
镇长？
Mayor?
镇长
Mayor.
镇长？
Mayor, are you there?
Mayor!
镇长？
Mayor?
镇长!
Mayor!
不，我是佛洛德
No, this is Floyd.
你要留话吗？
Can I take a message?
镇长!你没事了!
Mayor! You're okay!
荷顿!别乱动!停下来!
Horton! Horton! Stop! Stop it!
抱歉
Sorry.
你们下面刚刚一定很惨 真高兴你们没事
It must have been rough down there. I can't believe I found you.
我都快担心死了
You really had me worried.
老天!镇长先生是对的!
Say! The Mayor was right!
爸爸!爸爸!爸爸!
Daddy! Daddy! Daddy!
好了，我没事了 宝贝女儿你们也是
Okay, I'm all right, and so are you.
呼呼镇的镇民们!
Citizens of Whoville!
见过我们的朋友荷顿
I'd like you to meet our friend Horton.
他会帮助我们
He's going to help us!
交给我吧
I've got this.
我是议会主席…
This is the Chairman...
白痴!
Idiot!
你完蛋了!听见没？废弃物!
You're finished in this town! Is that understood? Finished.
大笨蛋!
You boob!
跟你开玩笑的啦
I'm just joking.
很好笑
Good one.
荷顿，这位是我太太，莎莉
Horton, this is my wife Sally.
你真的存在!
You exist!
这就表示我的老公没发疯
This means my husband isn't crazy.
好耶!
Hooray!
还有我几个女儿… 海莉、荷莉、胡莉、海达和海蒂
And a few of my daughters, Haley, Holly, Hooly, Hilda and Hedy.
-你好 -你好
- Hi! - Hi!
还有叶波小姐，我最得力的助手
And here is Miss Yelp, my loyal assistant.
-接着是拉鲁博士 -你救了我们!
- And here's Dr. Larue. - You saved us!
会计部的伯特
And Burt from accounting,
梅洁莉寇迪太太和法福根先生
and Mrs. McGillicuddy, and Mr. Farfoogan
他来自克鲁格法福根
from the Clugan Farfoogans,
还有在浴缸泡澡的老头
and the old man in the bathtub.
别折磨他了
Let's not overwhelm the poor fellow.
他不可能记得所有名字的
He's never gonna remember all these names.
我尽量试试看
Well, I'll try my best.
莎莉、主席
Sally, Chairman,
海莉、胡莉、荷莉…叶波小姐
Haley, Hooly, Holly, Hilda, Hedy, Miss Yelp,
拉鲁博士、会计部的伯特 梅洁莉寇迪太太、法福根先生
Dr. Larue, Burt from accounting, Mrs. McGillicuddy, Mr. Farfoogan
是不是有个老头在洗澡？
of the Clugan Farfoogans, and wasn't there an old guy in a shower?
泡澡
Bathtub.
-噢，差一点! -我们全都在这里，荷顿
- Yeah! - We're all here, Horton,
还有…我们全都相信你
and we all believe in you.
那真是太棒了
Wow. That's awesome.
我对于你们的承诺绝对不打折
And it's a responsibility I do not take lightly.
我保证你们会有一个 安稳又健全的未来
I promise you a future that is safe, sound and stable.
我们要开创一个世界 让大家都有国民年金跟老农津贴
We will create a world where every Who is endowed with three inalienable rights,
这是我们接下来必须做的
to be determined at a later date.
我们要把这粒小小的灰尘 在十年之内放到努尔山上去
And we will put a speck on Mount Nool before the end of this decade.
这只大象疯了!我的老天爷
This elephant is crazy! Oh, my goodness.
我得告诉大家，我要找袋鼠妈妈
I gotta tell everybody. I need to get to the Kangaroo.
等到他们发现就…
Wait till they find out about...
你该看看当时我有多猛 我狠狠教训了那只大象
You should have been seeing me. I really let elephant have it.
我追击他、折磨他 把那只大象撕烂成几百万个碎片
I chase him, I torment him, I break him into million little elephant pieces.
我这次干得漂亮，真的 最俐落的一次，维拉代表作
It was thing of beauty, really. My best work. Classic Vlad.
那朵苜蓿花呢？
And the clover?
它早毁了!荷顿别想找到它!
Clover is finished! No way in million years Horton find it.
读我的鸟嘴，苜蓿花已经氐淄甑傲
Read my beak. Clover is gone forever.
我刚看到荷顿还在跟那朵花说话
I just saw Horton, and he is still talking to that clover!
大饭桶!
Idiot!
我是你兄弟，你谈心的好对象 我们都是老朋友了
Whoa! Come on, I'm your bro! It's me you're talking to. We have history!
别忘了这一切还是免费服务
Come on, let's not forget, I did this for free!
努尔森林到底出了什么问题？
What is happening to the jungle of Nool?
这里以往都是居民归居民
There once was a time when people were people
小灰尘归小灰尘
and specks were specks.
那看不到、听不到或感觉不到的
Well, I say, "If you can't see it, hear it or feel it,
根本就不存在!
"it doesn't exist!"
我们的生活模式正受到破坏
Our way of life is under attack!
这是谁造成的？荷顿!
And who is leading that attack? Horton!
哗!哗!哗!
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
先等一等!现在说的是荷顿吗？
Wait a minute! This is Horton we're talking about.
我们都认识他，他连屁都不乱放
You all know him, he wouldn't hurt a fly.
除了那次把学生熏昏之外 但他绝对不是故意的
Except for that fly city he sat on. But he didn't do that on purpose.
闭嘴，臭老鼠!
Shut up, mouse!
当我没说，我的蛋糕快烤焦了 我该闪 了
That's weird. My brownies are burning. I gotta go!
我们真的要让荷顿这个惹祸精 毒害孩子们的心灵吗？
Are we going to let troublemakers like Horton poison the minds of our children?
孩子是无辜的!
Not the children!
当荷顿告诉孩子们 关于丛林以外的世界
When Horton tells our children about worlds beyond the jungle,
就是在质疑家长的权威
he makes them question authority!
导致孩子们的叛逆 导致社会陷入混乱
Which leads to defiance! Which leads to anarchy!
没错，荷顿要付出代价!
Yeah! Horton must pay!
都是小灰尘惹的祸
It's that speck!
我们必须采取行动
We have to do something!
为了孩子们!
For the children!
我们要让他就此逍遥法外吗？
Are we going to let him get away with this?
不
No!
我们去抓他
Let's go!
摩登!我说过，大象最讲信用!
Morton! I told you! 100%!
荷顿!
Horton!
摩登，脚步声轻一点，真是的
Morton, pick up your feet! Jeez.
我没那么重!
It's not me!
我知道了，是一群暴民 抱歉，摩登
I see. It's an angry mob. Sorry, Morton.
我还以为是你…
I thought it was you that was making all the...
不过这个…
But it's...
天啊
Oh, darn.
荷顿，快跑
Run, Horton!
他在那里!
There he is!
把他绑起来!
Let's rope him!
把他关起来!
Let's cage him!
不!不!不!
No! No! No!
停!
Stop!
各位，大家好
Hey, fellas. Good to see you,
全都到齐了
all at once.
你们还真声势浩大啊
You look really great as a horde.
荷顿、荷顿、荷顿
Horton, Horton, Horton,
看你为自己制造了多大的麻烦
look at the mess you've created for yourself.
全都是为了那朵小蠢花
All this hullabaloo over a silly little flower.
是一粒灰尘
It's a speck.
随便，这真是笨透了 这蠢东西害你被五花大绑
Right. I mean, it's silly, really, all this talk of roping you,
还要被关起来…不用说那么清楚
and caging you, and, well, we don't need to go into the details.
重点是，这群愤怒的群众 还有你制造的一切麻烦
The point is, this angry mob, all the trouble you're in,
全都能一笔勾消
it can all go away.
-真的？ -当然
- Really? - Of course.
你只需要向大家认错 承认那粒小小的灰尘上
All you have to do is admit to everyone that there are no little people
并没有住人
living on that speck.
承认你是错的，而我是对的
That you were wrong and I was right.
照我说的去做，一切就能回归正轨
You do that and things can go right back to the way they were.
但如果你不肯，你就准备付出代价吧
But if you don't, you're going to have to pay the price.
只要说一切都是假的就行了？
So, I just have to say it isn't true?
动手吧，绑我、关我 你们想怎样都行
Go ahead. Rope me, cage me. Do whatever you want.
但是灰尘上真的有住人
But there are people on this speck.
他们还有镇长，他有96个女儿 和一个叫乔乔的儿子
And they have a Mayor, who has 96 daughters and one son named JoJo,
他们共用一间厕所…管它是什么
who all share a bathroom, whatever that is,
虽然你们听不到也看不到他们
and even though you can't hear or see them at all,
万物生而平等，不论他们有多渺小
a person's a person, no matter how small.
说得可真动听，荷顿
That was beautiful, Horton.
绑住他!关起来!
Rope him! Cage him!
把那粒蠢灰尘丢到滚烫的热油里去
And burn that speck in a pot of boiling Beezlenut oil!
他们不相信我们在这里
They don't believe we're here.
我们必须制造点声音!
We've got to make some noise!
我们在这、我们在这、我们在这
We are here! We are here! We are here!
我们在这、我们在这
我们在这
We are here! We are here! We are here!
大声叫!
Come on!
-大家一起叫! -我们在这!我们在这!我们在这!
- Everybody! - We are here! We are here! We are here!
我们在这!我们在这!我们在这!
We are here! We are here! We are here!
这次教训是要告诉你 不要编那种灰尘上有人的故事
This will teach you not to make up stories about people on specks!
你们听!他们在这里!
Listen! There they are!
-绑住他 -关起来
- Rope him. - Cage him!
声音还不够大
It's not working.
我听得到，但他们听力不够好
I can hear you, but their ears aren't strong enough.
我们必须大声一点
We need to be louder!
大家都来制造噪音，一起来!
Get every Who to make noise! Everyone!
我们在这!我们在这!我们在这!
We are here! We are here! We are here!
乔乔!你要去哪里？
JoJo! Where are you going?
我们需要所有人的声音!乔乔!
We need every voice! JoJo!
声音必须再大一点 不然我们都完了!
You need to make some noise down there, or we'll all be destroyed!
镇长抓起了一对鼓槌 开始用力的打起来
The Mayor grabbed a tom-tom and started to smack it,
呼呼镇上上下下 全都卯足全力呼喊
and all over Whoville, they whooped up a racket.
他们拿出锡锅、敲打黄铜平底锅
They rattled tin kettles! They beat on brass pans!
脚踩垃圾桶和破铁罐
On garbage pail tops and old cranberry cans!
他们吹奏低音喇叭和大喇叭
They blew on bazookas and blasted great toots.
还有竖笛、巴松和长笛
On clarinets, oompahs, and boompahs, and flutes!
荷顿!
There!
他们现在听得到吗？
Can they hear us now?
快听啊，求求你们 这是我听过最美妙的声音
Listen, please. It's the most beautiful thing ever.
我什么也没听到
I don't hear nothing!
我想是没听到，继续试下去
I don't think so. But keep trying.
我绝对不放弃
I'll never give in!
你确定每个呼呼镇民 都有尽力制造声音吗？
Are you sure that every Who down in Whoville is trying?
我们在这!我们在这…
We are here! We are here!
乔乔人呢？
Where's JoJo?
大概又跑到旧天文台去了
Probably at the old observatory.
不要太过份了
Hey! There's a limit!
我的鼻子弹性没那么好
That's not supposed to stretch that far!
乔乔!
JoJo!
这些是你做的？
You built this?
我们在这!我们在这!我们在这!
We are here! We are here! We are here!
我们在这!我们在这!
我们在这!我们在这!我们在这!
We are here! We are here! We are here!
你大错特错了
You're making a mistake.
但是，妈!
But, Mom!
这不干你的事，回你房间去!
This doesn't concern you, sweetie. Back in your pouch!
大家注意!别停!
Everybody! Don't stop!
大家继续，这次一定有用!
Keep going! This is gonna do it!
我们在这!我们在这!我们在这!
We are here! We are here! We are here!
他们听到没？
Can they hear?
没!
No!
不管最后结果如何 你都是我最棒的儿子
No matter what happens, I couldn't ask for a better son.
乔乔!
Hey, JoJo!
继续，不要放弃!
Come on! Keep going!
不!
No!
我在这里!我在这里!我在这里!…
We are here! We are here! We are here!
不!
No!
唷!
Yopp!
我们在这!我们在这!我们在这!
We are here! We are here! We are here!
我听到了!我听到了!
I hear it! I hear it!
他们在那里!
They are there!
而那一声呼喊 那一声小小的呼喊冲破天际
And that Yopp, that one small extra Yopp put it over,
所有呼呼族的声音从花上传出来
and all the Who noises burst out of the clover.
-我听到了 -我也是
- I hear it! - Me, too!
儿子，把花给我!拿来…
Rudy. Give me that! Come...
儿子，快回到袋子里，听话
Rudy. Get back in the pouch. Now!
不要，妈
No, Mom.
猴子们，把那朵花拿来
Wickershams! Get that clover!
谁都可以!把花拿过来!
Anybody! Take it from him!
你成功了，镇长，你成功了
You did it, Mayor. You did it.
我们成功了!
We did it!
耶!
Yeah!
干得好，儿子
Well done, son.
干的好，镇长
All right, Mayor!
老爸，你进入名人堂了
Dad, you're one of the greats!
大家别激动，慢慢来
Whoa. Easy, everyone! Easy!
你好，维拉
Hi, Vlad.
其实我在减肥，管他的
Well, I shouldn't, but...
这一刻可真感人
Oh, man, that is nice touch.
我想我太感动了，对吗？ 我太情绪化，眼泪要决堤了
I am a mess with this, right? Emotional! Here come the waterslide.
我要感谢很多人
There's so many people to thank.
谢谢努尔的好居民
The good people of Nool,
把我关进牢里还用棍子戳我
who put me in a cage and poked me with sticks.
戳他的就是我!
That was me!
我的兄弟摩登，一直支持着我
My buddy Morton, for being the only one who stood by me.
也不算支持啦
Well, not right by me.
他躲在草丛里帮我出主意，他很小
He hid in the bushes, sending me good thoughts. He's small.
老兄，你还真是文武全才
Dude, you are a warrior poet.
最重要的是，我要感谢呼呼镇长
And most of all, I'd like to thank the Mayor of Whoville,
他从一开始就相信我
who believed in me from the beginning.
荷顿，我们会很想念你的
Horton, we're going to miss you.
荷顿，少了你我们该怎么办？
What are we gonna do without you, Horton?
别担心，我会永远守护你们
Don't worry. I'll always be around.
即使我在外流浪
And even as I wander
我仍设法看顾你
I'm keeping you in sight
你是窗畔的烛火
You're a candle in the window
照亮冰冷黑暗的冬夜
On a cold, dark winter's night
真美的比喻
Beautiful metaphor.
而我比我想像中
And I'm getting closer
更靠近你
Than I ever thought I might
这音调高了一点
That's a little high for me.
我再也无法克制这份情感
Baby, I can't fight this feeling anymore
我已忘记我是在抗拒什么
I've forgotten what I started fighting for
就算我得匍匐在你脚下
And if I have to crawl upon your floor
匍匐在你脚下
Crawl upon the floor
撞穿你家大门
Come crashing through your door
Crashing through your door
我再也无法克制…
Baby, I can't fight this feeling anymore
我再也无法克制这份情感
I can't fight this feeling anymore
从此荷顿和呼呼族 以及森林里所有动物
And so all ended well, for both Horton and Whos,
甚至袋鼠妈妈，都过得幸福美满
and for all in the jungle, even kangaroos.
这件事教导我们每一个人
So let that be a lesson, to one and to all.
万物生而平等，不论他们有多渺小
A person's a person, no matter how small.
我再也无法克制这份情感
And I can't fight this feeling anymore
我喜欢这样唱，快一点
Yeah, I like this. Faster, more up-tempo.
我已忘记我是在抗拒什么
I've forgotten what I started fighting for
我无法克制这份情感
I can't fight this feeling
是时候该让我这艘船停靠你岸头
It's time to bring my ship into your shore
好比喻!
That's a metaphor!
抛开船桨
And throw away the oar
又一个比喻
Another metaphor!
买个引擎
And buy an engine
我再也无法克制…这份情感
'Cause I can't fight this feeling anymore
从头到脚
From the weight of my trunk to my toes
我已忘记我是在抗拒什么
I've forgotten what I started fighting for
你不该抗拒什么，享受人生
Well, you shouldn't be fighting anything. Enjoy yourself.
就算我得匍匐在你脚下
If I have to crawl across the floor
-撞穿你家那扇烂门 -撞穿你家大门
- Now, break down your stupid door - Crashing through your door
我再也无法克制这份情感
Baby, I can't fight this feeling anymore
空着肚子怎么克制
On an empty stomach
我无法克制这份情感
I can't fight this feeling
我随便乱唱的啦
I'm just saying words.
唱歌的感觉真好，真是太爽了!
That felt so good. Cathartic!
怎样？
What?